40 chapter 41 of Black Beauty The LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 41 The Butcher I saw a great deal of trouble
among the horses in London, and much of it might have been prevented by little
common sense. We horses do not mind hard work if we are treated reasonably, and
I'm sure there are many driven by quite poor men who have a happier life than I
had when I used to go in the Countess of carriage, with my silver mounted harness and high
feeding. It often went to my heart to see how the little ponies we used, straining
along with heavy loads or staggering under heavy blows from some low, cruel
boy. Once I saw a little gray pony with a
thick mane and a pretty head, and so much like merry legs that if I had not been
in harness I should have Ned to him. He was doing his best to pull a heavy cart,
while a strong rough boy was cutting him under the belly with his whip and
chucking cruy at his little mouth. Could it be merry legs It was just like him;
but then Mr Bloomfield was never to sell him, and I think he would not do it; but
this might have been quite as good a little fellow, and had as happier place when he was
young. I often noticed the great speed at which butcher's horses were made to go,
though I did not know why it was so till
one day when we had to wait some time in St. John's Wood. There was a butcher shop
next door, and as we were standing a butcher's cart came dashing up at a great
pace. The horse was hot and much exhausted; he hung his head down, while
his heaving sides and trembling legs showed how hard he had been
driven. The lad jumped out of the cart and was getting the basket when the
master came out of the shop much displeased. After looking at the horse he
turned angrily to the lad. “How many times shall I tell tell you not to drive in
this way? You ruined the last horse and broke his wind, and you were going to
ruin this in the same way. If you were not my own son I would dismiss you on
the spot; it is a disgrace to have a horse brought to the shop in a condition
like that; you were liable to be taken up by the police for such driving, and if
you are you need not look to me for bail,
for I have spoken to you till I'm tired; you must look out for
yourself.” During this speech the boy had stood by, sullen and dogged, but when his
father ceased he broke out angrily. It wasn't his fault, and he wouldn't take
the blame; he was only going by orders all the time. “You always say, 'Now be quick; now
look sharp!' and when I go to the houses one wants a leg of mutton for an early
dinner and I must be back with it in the quarter of an hour; another cook has
forgotten to order the beef; I must go and fetch it and be back in no time, or
the mistress will scold; and the housekeeper says they have company
coming unexpectedly I must have some chops sent up directly; and the lady at number four in the
Cresent never orders her dinner till the meat comes in for lunch, and it's nothing
but hurry, hurry, all the time. If the gentry would think of what they want, and
order their meat the day before, there need not be this blow
up!” “I wish to goodness they would,” said the butcher it would save me a wonderful
deal of harass, and I could suit my customers much better if I knew
beforehand— —But there! what's the use of talking whoever thinks of a butcher's
convenience or a butcher's horse!
Now, then, take him in and look to him well; mind, he does not go out again today
and if anything else is wanted you must carry it yourself in the
basket.” With that he went in, and the horse was led
away. But all boys are not cruel. I have seen some as fond of their pony or
donkey as if it had been a favorite dog, and the little creatures have worked
away as cheerfully and willingly for their young drivers as I work for
Jerry. It may be hard work sometimes, but a friend's hand and voice make it
easy. There was a young Costa boy who came up our street with greens and
potatoes; he had an old pony, not very handsome, but the cheerfest and pluckiest
little thing I ever saw, and to see how fond those two were of each other was a
treat. The pony followed his master like a dog, and when he got into his cart
would trot off without a whip or a word, and rattle down the street as merrily as
if he had come out of the queen's stables.
Jerry liked the boy, and called him “Prince Charlie”, for he said he would make
a king of drivers someday There was an old man, too, who
used to come up our street with a little coal cart; he wore a coal he's hat, and
looked rough and black. He and his old horse used to plot together along the
street, like two good partners who understood each other; the horse would
stop of his own accord at the doors where they took coal of him; he used to
keep one ear bent towards his master. The old man's cry could be heard
up the street long before he came near. I never knew what he said, but the children
called him “Old ba ah who for it sounded like that. Polly took her Co of him, and
was very friendly, and Jerry said it was a comfort to think how happy an old
horse might be in a poor place end of chapter 41